TAMMY TIAN

012ttian@gmail.com 414-248-5586

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

github.com/tammyztian linkedin.com/in/tiantammy

Skills

ES6, ARIA, jQuery, React, Redux, React-Router, React-Intl, Express, Passport, Autho, Next.js, Cypress.io, Mocha, Chai, Enzyme, Apollo, GraphQL, Java/Spring, Jest, Python, Pandas, NumPy, NLP, Plotly, REST API, RegEx, MongoDB, SQL, PeopleSoft, Apache Nifi, Informatica, Autosys, Korn Shell Script, AWS S3, AWS Lambda, Travis CI, Netlify, Heroku, Terraform, Yeoman, Jira, Git, GitLab, Agile

Projects

Full stack Developer, Ally - https://github.com/tammyztian/ally-server AWS SNS, SQS, DynamoDb, Node.js, React.js
Ally is an undetectable way to notify trusted contacts when experiencing domestic violence with loved ones. By making it easy and undetectable to notify trusted contacts we remove a barrier to reaching out for help. We use AWs SNS to notify trusted contacts so the user's phone will have no trace of sending out a message when things don't feel right.

Full stack Developer, Ask Milwaukee - https://amzn.to/2XQxKpl Alexa Voice Skill Kit, AWS Lambda, Node.js
Ask City of Milwaukee is an Alexa App bringing the City's latest open data information to the user's home. This app
originated as the second place winner at Milwaukee's first all female hack-a-thon, Hack-A-Pipeline. It is now developed in
collaboration with the City of Milwaukee. It currently runs on Node.js using Lambda functions.

Full Stack Developer, John Deere Bookstore - johndeeretechinfo.com **Cypress, React, Node.js, Next.js GraphQL, Java** After ten years, John Deere is revamping their e-commerce site for publications. Their large line of products called for a massive overhaul of legacy code and databases and a cosmetic refresher.

Experience

Full Stack Developer, Northwestern Mutual

August 2019 - Present

- Utilize AWS to develop modernization services to a ten year old General Ledger batch process
- Engineered microservices using Java Spring and Node.js to extract and load data
- Create apache Nifi flows to consume and standardize data the load into different systems
- Transform hundreds of thousand lines of transaction data from different systems into General Ledger

Co-founder/DevOps Engineer, Policybot.io

Sept 2019 – Present

- Develop a code pipeline to allow for one push to deploy code into test, stage and production environments
- Migrate local database into AWS RDS for High Availability and fast compute power while running analytics
- Automate daily web scraping process from with AWS lambda and AWS Cloudfront
- Design, create and maintain company website using React, Gatsby and Contentful

Full Stack Developer, Ken Cook Co.

August 2018 – Sept 2019

- Assist in developing pipeline from development-to-test-to-deployment as team size grew
- Implement API calls from e-commerce site to our core services tax, shipping, credit card
- Integrate company database with client database with Apollo/GraphQL

Communications Assistant, Global Health Drug Discovery Institute (GHDDI)

December 2017 – March 2018

- Developed interactive add-ons to the website (follow social media buttons, sign-up for newsletter ect.)
- Drafted government-to-non-profit organization structure proposals for non-profit research institutions in Beijing
- Authored bi-monthly newsletter email included team interviews and research paper updates

Research Assistant, Wisconsin China Initiative

November 2014 - November 2017

- Established the first student orientation in China for the University of Wisconsin-Madison
- Launched coursework and campus events to increase interest in modern China studies
- Mentored a team of four undergraduates in developing events and outreach opportunities

Education and Training

AWS Cloud Practitioner
Second Place, Hack-A-Pipeline
Full-Time Engineering Immersion Program

Amazon Web Services Lift Up Milwaukee Thinkful

Bachelor's of Science, Journalism and Mass Communication, East Asian Studies